在我们讨论二维世界的前一讲中，我们介绍了这个概念
In the previous lecture when we were discussing 2-dimensional worlds, we introduced the concept
右手坐标系。
of a right-handed coordinate frame.
而且，只是提醒你，右手坐标系就是这样构造的。
And, just to remind you, the right-handed coordinate frame is constructed like this.
我们绘制x轴，然后我们将y轴向上摆动90度。
We draw the x-axis and then we swing the y-axis up by 90 degrees.
三维坐标系实际上非常类似于二维坐标
A three-dimensional coordinate frame is actually very similar to the two-dimensional coordinate
帧。
frame.
所以，这是我们刚才介绍的二维右手坐标系。
So, here is the two-dimensional right-handed coordinate frame that we just introduced.
而且，我现在要做的是在三维空间中旋转它。
And, what I’m going to do do now is to rotate that in three dimensions.
而且，我们看到的是z轴以前是隐藏的。
And, what we see is that the z-axis was previously hidden.
以前，它在屏幕上突然出现在我们面前。
Previously, it was sticking up at us out of the screen.
为了创建一个三维右手坐标系，我们以类似的方式开始。
To create a 3-dimensional right-handed coordinate frame, we start in a similar way.
我们绘制x轴。
We draw the x-axis.
我们摆动y轴，使其与x轴成90度角。
We swing the y-axis so that it makes an angle of 90 degrees to the x-axis.
然后，我们向上摆动z轴，它也与z轴成90度角
And then, we swing the z-axis upwards and it also makes an angle of 90 degrees to the
x轴也与y轴成90度角。
x-axis and also makes an angle of 90 degrees to the y-axis.
二维和三维坐标之间存在非常密切的关系
There’s a very close relationship between the 2-dimensional and the 3-dimensional coordinate
帧。
frames.
让我放下二维坐标系，这里是三维坐标
Let me put down the two-dimensional coordinate frame and here is three-dimensional coordinate
帧。
frame.
并且，我可以覆盖x轴和y轴，我们看到z轴指向上方。
And, I can overlay the x-axis and the y-axis and we see that the z-axis points upwards.
我们将其称为右手坐标系。
We refer to this as a right-handed coordinate frame.
而且，我们称之为右手框架的原因是轴的方向可以是
And, the reason we call it a right-handed frame is the orientation of the axes can be
非常简单地用右手定义。
defined very simply using my right hand.
所以，这是x轴。
So, this is the x-axis.
这是y轴。
This is the y-axis.
而且，这是指向上方的z轴。
And, this is the z-axis pointing upwards.
因此，每当我们使用三维坐标框架时，它们总是右手
So, whenever we’re doing work with 3-dimensional coordinate frames, they are always right-handed
坐标框架。
coordinate frames.
我建立的这个特殊坐标系，我们有一个x轴和一个y轴，这个，
This particular coordinate frame that I built, we have an x-axis and a y-axis and this one,
z轴指向下方。
the z-axis pointing downwards.
这是一个左手坐标系。
This is a left-handed coordinate frame.
所以最好不要使用它们，它们会给你带来各种各样的悲伤。
So it’s best not to use these, they are going to cause you all sorts of grief.
所以，不要使用左手坐标系。
So, don’t use left-handed coordinate frames.
使用右手坐标系。
Go with the right-handed coordinate frame.
所以，回顾一下。
So, just to recap.
当我们创建一个右手坐标系时，我们使用这个称为右手的规则
When we create a right-handed coordinate frame, we use this rule what’s called the right-handed
规则，我拿右手。
rule, and I take my right hand.
x轴与我的拇指平行。
The x-axis is parallel to my thumb.
y轴平行于我的食指。
The y-axis is parallel to my index finger.
并且，z轴平行于我的中指。
And, the z-axis is parallel to my middle finger.